嘿,妈妈。妈妈!看那。
Hey, Mama. Mom! Look at that.
看,妈妈,你看。
Look, Mommy, look.
约翰尼!
Johnny!
现在你让妈妈做代言人。记住。
Now you let Mommy do the talking. Remember.
是的,妈妈。
Yes, Mom.
但他没有马。
But he has no horse.
没有说话。
No talking.
早上好。
Good morning.
-你看起来像你有麻烦。 - 是的。
- You look like you've had trouble. - Yep.
我失去了我的马前几天远离一些印度人。
I lost my horse a few days ago getting away from some Indians.
印度人吗?
Indians?
我们昨晚干营Ilano之上。
We made dry camp last night above the Ilano.
萨姆在这里闻起来更阿帕奇人,蹭我。
Sam here smelled more Apaches, nuzzled me up.
所以我想把一些我们之间的距离。
So I thought I'd put some miles between us.
但是为什么呢?我们在和平与Apache。
But why? We're at peace with the Apache.
- 我们有一个条约。 - 是的,夫人。
- We have a treaty. - Yes, ma'am.
现在我必须把我的新马,借或买一个。
Now I got to get me a new horse, borrow or buy one.
我可以支付你在美国的脚本。我骑调度一般骗子。
I can pay you in United States script. I'm riding a dispatch for General Crook.
- 我的名字叫巷。 - 我是劳夫人。
- My name's Lane. - I'm Mrs. Lowe.
我是强尼。
I'm Johnny.
- 水看起来诱人。 - 嗯,帮助自己。
- The water sure looks inviting. - Well, help yourself.
当心那只狗,儿子。
Watch out for that dog, son.
你能雇佣我或给我一匹马,罗伊太太吗?
Could you hire me or sell me a horse, Mrs. Lowe?
当然。我只有耕马,和两只活。
Of course. I've only got plow horses, and two that are only half-broken.
打破他们的手为我是受伤了,不得不去城镇。
The hand that was breaking them for me got hurt and had to go to town.
- 你的意思是你住这儿吗?-哦,不。
- You mean you're staying here alone? - Oh, no.
不,我的丈夫是在山上……
No, my husband is up in the hills...
- 工作一些牛。-哦。
- working some cattle. - Oh.
他会挑选今天要离开,当我们有一个客人。
He would pick today to be away, when we have a visitor.
我喜欢认识他,夫人。
I'd enjoy meeting him, ma'am.
我不会碰那只狗,儿子。他不需要爱抚。
I wouldn't touch that dog, son. He don't take to petting.
现在如果你会允许,夫人,我就看看那些马。
And now if you'll allow, ma'am, I'll take a look at those horses.
当然。你会发现一个鞍的谷仓。
Of course. You'll find a saddle over by the barn.
与此同时,我将给你点吃的。我想象你饿了。
In the meantime, I'll fix you something to eat. I imagine you're hungry.
我可以吃。谢谢你！
I could eat. Thank you.
我很抱歉我的丈夫不得不选择今天去打猎的那些失去了小牛。
I'm so sorry my husband had to pick today to go hunting those lost calves.
他很有可能会喜欢有一个人说话。
He would have enjoyed having a man to talk to.
我们欢迎游客。
We welcome visitors.
在这里Ionely肯定是正确的。尤其对一个女人。
Must be right Ionely around here. Especially for a woman.
我不介意。我在这里长大。
I don't mind. I was raised here.
- 我可以喂你的狗吗? - 没有,谢谢。
- What can I feed your dog? - Nothing, thanks.
他做了他自己。可以超越任何在兔子的领土。
He makes out by himself. Can outrun any rabbit in the territory.
一点儿也不麻烦。
It's no trouble at all.
如果你不介意,太太,我宁愿你没有喂他。
If you don't mind, ma'am, I'd rather you didn't feed him.
我看到。你不想让他得到进食的习惯从别人。
I see. You don't want him to get in the habit of taking food from anyone else.
嗯,你可以把这个交给他。
Well, you can hand it to him.
不,小姐,我不让他吃,要么。山姆的独立。
No, ma'am, I don't feed him, either. Sam's independent.
他不需要任何人。我希望他能保持这种方式。
He doesn't need anybody. I want him to stay that way.
这是一个好方法。
It's a good way.
- 每个人都需要别人。 - 是的,夫人。大多数人。
- Everyone needs someone. - Yes, ma'am. Most everyone.
太糟糕了,不是吗?
Too bad, isn't it?
- 你是一个好厨师,夫人。 - 谢谢你。
- You're a good cook, ma'am. - Thank you.
一个女人应该是一个好厨师。好厨师自己。
A woman should be a good cook. Good cook myself.
你为什么不让他当他被卡住了?
Why didn't you get on him when he was stuck?
因为我不想让他坐在我从一站开始。
'Cause I didn't want him sitting on me from a standing start.
同他住。
Stay with him.
你选择了最野蛮的人。
You chose the most savage one.
我不会给你一个论点。
I won't give you an argument there.
他一直都是一个斗士。
He's always been a fighter.
我不会给一个插镍为马,不会打架。
I wouldn't give a plugged nickel for a horse that wouldn't fight.
它让你失望当情况变得艰难。
It lets you down when the going gets tough.
有点单调。
It's a little dull.
嗯,我可以做几乎任何事情在一个牧场,但我永远不可能…
Well, I can do almost everything around a ranch, but I never could...
把一个边缘一把斧头。
put an edge on an axe.
它在哪儿呢?
Where is it?
-什么? - 的磨刀石。
- What? - The grindstone.
这个农场看起来像是这里一会儿。
This ranch looks like it's been here a little while.
是的,我出生在这里。我的丈夫在这里长大,太。
Yes, I was born here. My husband was raised here, too.
他是一个孤儿。他的父母被杀在马车队屠杀……
He's an orphan. His parents got killed in a wagon-train massacre...
所以我父亲带他在。
so my father took him in.
-方便。-你什么意思?
- Handy. - What do you mean?
好吧,看来这个数字是反对它。
Well, it seems the figures are against it.
只有轻的研究员在1000平方英里…
Only young fellow in 1,000 square miles...
只有轻的女孩在1000平方英里。
only young girl in 1,000 square miles.
他们会在旋转中超过对方。这就是我的意思。方便的。
They get in a whirl over each other. That's what I meant. Handy.
我想这是一个巧合。
I guess it was quite a coincidence.
但是他们说正确的两人要满足的命运的安排。
But they say that the right two people are going to meet by an arrangement of destiny.
你相信,洛太太吗?
You believe that, Mrs. Lowe?
- 是的,我喜欢。 - 有趣。
- Yes, I do. - Interesting.
总是沉叶片成日志,儿子。使边缘清洁。
Always sink a blade into a log, son. Keeps the edge clean.
嗯,我想我最好退出失速,回到那匹马。
Well, I guess I'd better quit stalling and get back to that horse.
和我可以玩山姆现在?
And can I play with Sam now?
我已经告诉你两次不来。
I've told you twice not to.
但是你做你想做的。
But you do what you wanna do.
真的,莱恩先生,如果你知道这狗会咬人,我想……
Really, Mr. Lane, if you knew the dog would bite, I should think...
罗伊太太,人学习让钻头。轻人刚学。
Mrs. Lowe, people learn by getting bit. Youngster just learned.
约翰尼。
Johnny.
不要碰那个狗了!现在进去把你的小睡。
Don't you ever touch that dog again! Now go in and take your nap.
而我在这,我将鞋这些犁马。
While I'm at it, I'll shoe those plow horses.
非常感谢你。他们需要一个修蹄,我猜。
Thank you very much. They do need a shoeing, I guess.
他们做的。
They do.
我想我的丈夫的很难找到那些迷路的小腿。
I guess my husband's having a hard time finding those strayed calves.
我猜他是。
I guess he is.
也许他不会回家直到今晚……
Perhaps he won't be home until late tonight...
或者他可能连山上的营地中,明天来在你死后。
or he may even camp in the hills and come in tomorrow after you're gone.
他会因此很抱歉错过我们的一个很少有偶尔的来访者。
He'll be so sorry to have missed one of our very few occasional visitors.
我想我要去照顾约翰尼。
I guess I'll go and look after Johnny.
罗伊太太,你是一个骗子。
Mrs. Lowe, you're a liar.
- 和一个全能的可怜的骗子。-我不懂你。
- And an almighty poor liar. - I don't understand you.
这些马没有穿鞋的一两个月。
These horses haven't been shod in a couple of months.
这是小事一桩,斧还没有优势,在两个月。
It's a cinch that axe hasn't had an edge on it in two months.
和你的茶可以,5磅的茶可以在你的房子是空的。
And your tea can, a five-pound tea can in your house is empty.
你的丈夫已经消失了很长一段时间。
Your husband's been gone a long time.
现在,看这里,莱恩先生,我不认为你有任何权利……
Now, look here, Mr. Lane, I don't think you have any right to...
我不谈论权利。我所说的谎言。
I'm not talking about rights. I'm talking about lies.
你为什么对我撒谎,罗伊太太吗?
Why did you lie to me, Mrs. Lowe?
是你害怕,也许你就不会和我在这儿安全与你的丈夫了吗?
Were you afraid that maybe you wouldn't be safe here with me with your husband away?
- 它吗? - 这部分是它。
- That it? - That's partly it.
女人总是图每一个男人的出现希望他们。
Women always figure every man comes along wants them.
-雷恩。 - 是的,夫人?
- Mr. Lane. - Yes, ma'am?
你是对的。我在撒谎。我的丈夫是过期。
You're right. I was lying. My husband is overdue.
他应该回家很久以前。
He should have been home long ago.
图阿帕奇人杀了他?
Figure Apaches killed him?
当然不是。有一百个可能的解释。
Of course not. There are a hundred possible explanations.
印度人是其中之一。
Indians are one of them.
但是我们在和平与Apache,除了少数……
But we're at peace with the Apache, except for a few...
罗伊太太,如果你有良好的感觉……
Mrs. Lowe, if you've got good sense...
你会收拾你和那个男孩的你跟我出来。
you'll pack up you and that boy of yours and come out with me.
那是在酝酿麻烦在Apache的小屋。
There's trouble brewing in the Apache lodges.
维托利奥,他们主要的首席,称为战争委员会。
Vittorio, their main chief, called a war council.
一个完整的报告是在分派我携带。
A full report of it is in that dispatch I'm carrying.
但是你不知道,我们一直相处得壮观与Apache。
But you don't know, we've always gotten along splendidly with the Apache.
他们喝酒,把他们的马,我们的春天……
They drink and bring their horses to our spring...
在北到野牛追捕。
on their way north to the buffalo hunt.
我从没见过伟大的维托利奥,但已经足够的阿帕奇人这里。
I've never seen the great Vittorio, but there've been plenty of Apaches here.
我看到伟大的维托利奥,在本条约。
I've seen the great Vittorio, before the treaty.
他的马已经40头皮挂在它的鬃毛。
His horse had 40 scalps hung in its mane.
这是以前的条约。
That was before the treaty.
我们打破了该条约,美国白人。
We broke that treaty, us Whites.
没有的话在Apache语言撒谎,并且他们被骗了。
There's no word in the Apache language for lie, and they've been lied to.
如果它们上升,不会有……
If they rise, there won't be...
- 一个白左在领土。 - 他们不会打扰我。
- a White left in the territory. - They won't bother me.
我们,我的意思是。我们总是相处得很好。
Us, I mean. We always got along very well.
我认识的人,男人和他的妻子相处真正好……
People I know, man and his wife, got along real well for...
20。然后有一天……
20 years. Then one day...
她增加了一个大洞,在他…
she upped and blew a hole in him...
大到足以驱动一辆公共马车通过。
big enough to drive a stagecoach through.
她疯了。阿帕切人疯了。
She got mad. The Apaches are mad.
好吧,我没有什么好担心的,我肯定。
Well, I have nothing to worry about, I'm sure.
很高兴被确定。
Nice to be sure.
让开。
Get out of the way.
- 奇怪的狗你有。 - 我没有他。
- Strange dog you have. - I don't have him.
- 你们两个在一起。 - 他依然和我在一起。
- The two of you are together. - He stays with me.
- 他可以闻到了印度在半英里。 - 他气味印第安人吗?我不相信它。
- He can smell an Indian at a half a mile. - He smells Indians? I don't believe it.
当然,很多狗闻到印第安人。你可以教他们。
Sure, lots of dogs smell Indians. You can teach them.
教他们吗?如何?
Teach them? How?
首先你准备一个小狗,然后……
First you get yourself a puppy and then...
你雇佣自己一个驯服的印度和削减一个柳树开关。
you hire yourself a tame Indian and cut a willow switch.
然后你得到印度打小狗……
Then you get the Indian to beat the puppy...
与柳开关四到五次一天。
with a willow switch four or five times a day.
当他长大了,他会总是信号当他闻到一个印度。
And when he grows up, he'll always signal when he smells an Indian.
打一只小狗。多么残忍。
Beat a puppy. How cruel.
这是他们的方式做它。
That's the way they do it.
无论如何,我不相信狗能闻到印第安人。
Anyway, I don't believe a dog can smell Indians.
我的意思是,不同于其他任何人。
I mean, as different from anyone else.
- 你或我,例如。 - 好吧,他们可以。
- You or me, for instance. - Well, they can.
作为一个事实,印度人能闻到白人。
As a matter of fact, Indians can smell White people.
- 我不相信它。 - 好吧,这是真的。
- I don't believe it. - Well, it's true.
我有部分印度,我能闻到你当我顺风的你。
I'm part Indian, and I can smell you when I'm downwind of you.
- 那是不可能的。 - 不,它不是不可能的,劳夫人。
- That's impossible. - No, it isn't impossible, Mrs. Lowe.
你烤的今天。我可以闻到新鲜的面包在你。
You baked today. I can smell fresh bread on you.
今天你煮的某个时候和咸肉。
Sometime today you cooked with salt pork.
闻,你,太。
Smell that on you, too.
你闻起来都像肥皂。
You smell all over like soap.
你洗个澡。和最重要的是,你闻起来都像一个女人。
You took a bath. And on top of that, you smell all over like a woman.
我能找到你在黑暗中,罗伊太太,我只有部分印度。
I could find you in the dark, Mrs. Lowe, and I'm only part Indian.
罗伊太太。
Mrs. Lowe.
你想要什么?
What do you want?
- 我浇水和粒度的股票。 - 谢谢你。
- I watered and grained the stock. - Thank you.
我将睡在附近某处今晚。
I'll bed down near here someplace tonight.
Lane先生吗?
Mr. Lane?
你不能在外面过夜,暴风雨就要来了。
You can't sleep outside, there's a storm coming.
我已经修正了托盘给你在角落里。
I've fixed a pallet for you in the corner.
这将是未开化的让任何人睡在外面……
It would be uncivilized to let anyone sleep outside...
毕竟,我们是文明的,不是吗?
and after all, we are civilized, aren't we?
为你说话,当然。但我呢?
Speaking for you, of course. But me?
我猜你会叫我文明。
I guess you could call me civilized.
那是你的床。我很抱歉必须在地板上。
That's your bed. I'm sorry it has to be on the floor.
我已经设置为早上面糊。我希望不会打扰你的噪音。
I have to set the batter for the morning. I hope the noise won't disturb you.
它不会。
It won't.
晚上好,夫人。
Good night, ma'am.
你把枪放下。
Put that gun down.
你是本州巷,枪手。
You're Hondo Lane, the gunman.
- 我带着枪。 - 别再接近。
- I carry a gun. - Don't come any nearer.
你杀了三个人在去一场枪战。
You killed three men in a gunfight last year.
- 我们听说过。三个男人。 - 是的,夫人。
- We heard about it. Three men. - Yes, ma'am.
- 就像快我可以。 - 别再接近。
- Just as quick as I could. - Don't come any nearer.
这不是一个好主意点这些东西之一在任何人……
It's not a very good idea to point one of these things at anybody...
用一个空腔在撞针。
with an empty chamber under the firing pin.
你可以看到它像天纯。
You can see it plain as day.
我保持这种方式,因为约翰尼。
I keep it that way because of Johnny.
嗯,现在它的加载。
Well, now it's loaded.
保持这种方式,保持高。
Keep it that way, and keep it high.
请留下来。我真的想要你。
Please stay. I really want you to.
我很抱歉。我应该意识到从一开始,你是一个绅士。
I'm sorry. I should have realized from the beginning that you are a gentleman.
文明吗?绅士?
Civilized? Gentleman?
嗯,很多一天。
Well, a lot for one day.
晚上,女士。
Night, ma'am.
早.... 早起。
Morning. Getting an early start.
一定要告诉那个小男人再见我。
Be sure and tell that little man goodbye for me.
我应该叫醒他向你告别。
I ought to wake him to say goodbye to you.
这是我,我让他睡。
Was it me, I'd let him sleep.
轻人成长睡觉,但是你做你想做的事。
Youngsters grow sleeping, but you do what you want to.
他是如此的高兴,你为他吹口哨。
He was so delighted with that whistle you made for him.
很高兴听到它。他和我相处很好。
Glad to hear it. He and I got along just fine.
它更像是一个比一个哨子吹长笛。它的范围几乎完整的规模。
It's more like a flute than a whistle. It ranges almost the full scale.
我学会了让他们当我是活在Mescalero。
I learned to make them when I was living with the Mescalero.
我的妻子用来使他们对每个孩子都在小屋。
My squaw used to make them for every kid in the lodge.
- 你住与Apache吗?- 5。
- You lived with the Apache? - Five years.
- 和你有一个印度的妻子吗? - 妻子,妻子...
- And you had an Indian wife? - Wife, squaw...
我随意的借几英尺的绳索从,线圈在披屋。
I took the liberty of borrowing a few feet of rope off of that coil in the lean-to.
- 为它付你钱的,如果你让我。 - “当然不。
- Gladly pay you for it, if you let me. - 'Course not.
今天的山是如此美丽。
The hills are so beautiful today.
怎么奇怪清楚他们总是在沙尘暴。
Odd how clear they always are after a dust storm.
一定是很有趣的生活与Apache。
Must have been very interesting living with the Apache.
我很喜欢它。
I liked it.
- 这个印度的妻子你有...。- 她死了。
- This Indian wife you have... - Had. She's dead.
我很抱歉。我不是有意要抚养一个不愉快的回忆。
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to bring up an unhappy memory.
我不记得任何事情Destarte不满。
I can't remember anything unhappy about Destarte.
Destarte吗? 怎样的音乐。这意味着什么呢?
Destarte? How musical. What does it mean?
你不能说它在Mescalero除外。这意味着早上。
You can't say it except in Mescalero. It means morning.
但这并不意味着什么,要么。
But that isn't what it means, either.
不仅仅意味着,。印度的字的意思是声音和…
Means more than just that. Indian words mean the sound and...
一个单词的感觉,就像……
feel of a word, like...
黎明,第一个青铜灯……
crack of dawn, the first bronze light...
这使山丘坚决反对灰色的沙漠。
that makes the buttes stand out against the gray desert.
你听到的第一个声音的一条小溪……
The first sound you hear of a brook...
在一些岩石冰壶,鲑鱼跳跃。
curling over some rocks, with trout jumping.
这就像当你起床在第一光……
It's like when you get up in the first light...
只有你和她,你离开一个窝棚。
just you and her and you go out of a wickiup.
它闻起来种烟熏和私人,只有你和她,……
Where it smells kind of smoky and private, just you and her, and...
种安全只有你们两个。
kind of safe with just the two of you.
站在外面……
Stand outside and...
觉得咬下来的第一个风从高分裂……
feel the bite of the first wind coming down from the high divide...
承诺的降雪。
that promises snowfall.
不能用英语说,但那是她的名字。
Can't say it in English, but that was her name.
Destarte。
Destarte.
- 你让我想起她一些。 - 印度的一个女孩?
- You remind me of her some. - Of an Indian girl?
她是公平的吗?
Was she fair?
她的头发是黑如10英尺下降。
Her hair was black as 10 feet down.
你有没有看到一只乌鸦的翅膀,黑色和闪闪发光的吗?
Did you ever see a crow's wing, how black and gleaming it is?
- 是的。 - 她的头发擦过。
- Yes. - That's the way her hair shined.
我想付你的绳索。
I'd like to pay you for that rope.
骑调度,我有权给美国脚本。
Riding dispatch, I have the right to give U.S. Script.
- 你爱她吗? - 我不知道。
- You loved her? - I don't know.
我需要她。
I needed her.
- 但如果她是黑暗和我公平… - 为什么你让我想起她吗?
- But if she was dark and I'm fair... - Why you reminded me of her?
- 是的。 - 我不知道。
- Yes. - I don't know.
我想到它。你看起来不像她的东西。
I thought about it. You don't look anything like her.
我完全意识到我是一个平凡的女人,雷恩。
I am fully aware that I am a homely woman, Mr. Lane.
我不是那个意思。
I didn't mean that.
我有一个坏习惯,实话实说。但漂亮并不多。
I have a bad habit of telling the truth. But being pretty isn't much.
我知道很多漂亮的人我不会相信……
I know a lot of pretty people I wouldn't trust...
与一个被镀镍手表。
with a busted nickel-plated watch.
但是另外一些人,出来的东西里,……
But some others, something comes out of the inside of them and...
你知道你可以信任他们。
you know you can trust them.
Destarte过。
Destarte had that.
和你有它,太。
And you've got it, too.
- 我是一个已婚女人。 - 我考虑到这一点了。
- I'm a married woman. - I thought about that, too.
我想我吻了你,因为你让我想起Destarte。
I guess I kissed you because you remind me of Destarte.
或许这是因为我讨厌觉得你的头发…
Or maybe it was because I hate to think of your hair...
挂在中心杆的一个Apache简陋的小屋。
hanging from the center pole of an Apache wickiup.
嗯,很久以前我让我一个规则。
Well, a long time ago I made me a rule.
我让人们做他们想做的事。
I let people do what they want to do.
山姆!
Sam!
你是一个奇怪的男人,雷恩。
You are a strange man, Mr. Lane.
我不知道。再见,劳夫人。
I don't know about that. Goodbye, Mrs. Lowe.
- 你是维托利奥。 - 我是维托利奥。
- You are Vittorio. - I am Vittorio.
你的马在这里被淡化。
Your horses have been watered here.
- 你被告知去。 - 我不能离开。
- You were told to go. - I couldn't leave.
我的丈夫不在,我不认为我 …
My husband is away, and I didn't think that I...
你的人在这里水他们的马。
Your people water their horses here.
你离开我的母亲独自一人。
You leave my mother alone.
阻止他!阻止他!
Stop him! Stop him!
-我不是害怕你。 - 你不恐惧Apache吗?
- I ain't scared of you. - You're not fear Apache?
没有。
No.
他害怕伤害到母亲,但不是自我。
He fear hurt to mother, but not that to self.
他勇敢的。像Apache的男孩。
He brave. Like Apache boy.
他现在结拜兄弟。我叫他小战士。
Him now blood brother. I call him Small Warrior.
他属于月亮狗旅馆,Chiricahua Apache。
Him belong Moon Dog Lodge, Chiricahua Apache.
你照顾他。你现在的母亲Chiricahua战士。
You care for him well. You now mother Chiricahua warrior.
安全的生活在这里。
Live safely here.
我希望有一天,有人与你的儿子。
I hope someday, someone befriends your sons.
我的儿子已经死了。白人杀死他们。
My sons are dead. White man kill them.
认为你的头皮会被悬挂在一些Apache窝棚现在。
Figured your scalp would be hanging in some Apache wickiup by now.
- 嗨,水牛。 - 是在下注。
- Hi, Buffalo. - Been making bets on it.
- 你肯定失望的我,本州。 - 你想赢得你的打赌。
- You're sure a disappointment to me, Hondo. - You like to win your bet.
我穿了一些马匹。
I wore out some horses.
你穿着你当你是在它。在这里,让我得到这个。
You wore out you while you was at it. Here, let me get that.
这是哪里的水吗?
Where's that water?
- 看起来像我打赌,水牛。 - 嗨,迪克。
- Looks like I won a bet, Buffalo. - Hi, Dick.
是的,我欠你一壶红眼。
Yeah, I owe you a jug of red-eye.
- 这感觉很好。 - 有次当水是好的。
- This feels good. - There's times when water is good.
这正是我的意思。
That's exactly what I mean.
我说我有权利在这里谈谈弓收缩的主要…
I say I got a right to talk to this here bow-necked Major...
- 我不要跟没有下属。 - 主要的睡着了。
- I don't talk to no underlings. - Major's asleep.
这只是他太差劲了。我是一个公民,我想去看他。
That's just too bad about him. I'm a citizen and I want to see him.
主要不是也没睡三天。
Major ain't had any sleep for three days.
我可以告诉你一切一样他可以。
I can tell you everything just as well as he can.
我们不是没接到了北。
We ain't heard nothing from up north.
如果你问我,骑兵的害怕维托利奥。我认为美国骑兵……
If you ask me, the Cavalry's scared of Vittorio. I think the U.S. Cavalry...
我非常喜欢你的观点的美国骑兵。
I am greatly interested in your opinion of the United States Cavalry.
继续, Mr... 无论你的名字是。
Continue, Mr... Whatever your name is.
骑兵应该支持定居者。
The Cavalry is supposed to support the settlers.
我有一些牛在北边,我不打算……
I've got some cattle up north, I don't intend...
C队伍正在扫描到北护送出任何移民他们可能发现。
C troop is making a sweep to the north to escort out any settlers they may find.
C一个多星期队伍是现在晚在返回。那是我能告诉你。
C troop is now over a week late in returning. That's all I can tell you.
C队伍不会回来。
C troop isn't coming back.
我很感激,先生,如果你将离开。
I'd be obliged, sir, if you would leave.
一个好业务,整个领地……
A fine business, the whole territory...
,长官! - 得到!
- Sergeant! - Get!
滚开,你这个肮脏的…
Get out of the way, you mangy...
- 如果这是你的坏蛋,让他出。-走在他周围。
- lf that's your cur, get him out of the way. - Walk around him.
我将挂如果我出去我的路对于任何杂狗狗。
I'll be hanged if I go out of my way for any cur dog.
一个人应该做自己认为是最好的。
A man ought to do what he thinks is best.
退出挡住了门。
Quit blocking the door.
你从哪里搞到的?
Where did you get this?
- 半个天南的双峰的骑。 - 如何?
- Half a day's ride south of Twin Buttes. - How?
把它从几个印度人,阿帕奇人。
Took it off a couple of Indians, Apaches.
走狗的Mescaleros住宿。
Running Dog Lodge of the Mescaleros.
Mescaleros上升,太。 让所有Apache小屋。
Mescaleros are up, too. That makes all the Apache lodges.
说,虽然我是南,没有移民得到从北方盆地?
Say, while I was south, did any settlers get in from the north basin?
一些,过去的几周。
A few, the last couple of weeks.
漂亮的女人,公平,一个男孩约六?
Handsome woman, fair, with a boy about six?
没有,大多是中或老人。
No, mostly middle-aged or elderly people.
得到一些睡眠,车道,用我的帐篷。
Get some sleep, Lane, use my tent.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
当你睡觉,我将移动你的可能的人选到我帐篷。
While you're sleeping, I'll move your possibles over to my tent.
皮特・布里顿是侦察与C队伍。
Pete Britton was scouting with C troop.
冬用旧皮特曾经的鸿沟。坏脾气的家伙。
Wintered with old Pete once up on the Divide. Ornery cuss.
他们印度人你带,彭南特开门营业的。
Them indians you took that pennant offen.
- 死印度人吗? - 最后。
- Dead Indians? - Finally.
- 你好,皮特。 - 嗨,本州。
- Hi, Pete. - Hi, Hondo.
伤了我的心,当我听到你做的。
Broke my heart when I heard you made it.
你知道你开始反对人民行动党这所谓的威士忌?
Your pap know you started out against this so-called whiskey?
我没见过他一个月。
I ain't seen him for a month.
我知道你没有。来这里,我得到了一个消息给你。
I know you haven't. Come here, I got a message for you.
离开他,本州,我无法使没有钱球探。
Leave him be, Hondo, I can't make no money scouting.
噢,这些其他的家伙会原谅你。在吧台上过来。
Aw, these other fellows'll excuse you. Come on over at the bar.
我不会。我走了100美元。
I won't. I'm out almost $100.
- 数字,水牛在游戏中。-等待一分钟。
- That figures, with Buffalo in the game. - Wait a minute.
这些衬衫都难。
These shirts are hard to come by.
- 你怎么打我? - 因为我知道你。
- What'd you hit me for? - 'Cause I know you.
皮革它。
Leather it.
不,不要皮它。
No, don't leather it.
难怪他们阿帕奇人叫他 Emberato。
No wonder them Apaches call him Emberato.
- 这意味着什么呢? - 坏脾气。
- What does it mean? - Bad temper.
我应该让他拍你。
I should've let him shoot you.
这是我第二次已经彻底打败,说大话的无用的…
That's the second time I've tangled with that mouthy no-good...
- 他叫什么名字? - 自称劳,艾德劳。
- What's his name? - Calls himself Lowe, Ed Lowe.
约翰尼。
Johnny.
约翰尼!
Johnny!
妈妈。
Mommy.
嗨,妈妈。维托利奥说我会成为一个好Apache。
Hi, Mommy. Vittorio says I'll make a good Apache.
我认为… 我不知道他是和你在一起,我什么都没听说。
I thought... I didn't know he was with you, I didn't hear anything.
- Apache没有制造噪音。 - 看看他给我。
- Apache no make noise. - Look what he gave me.
- 这是洛奇令牌。他的 - 这是非常漂亮的,谢谢你。
- It is lodge token. His. - It's very pretty, thank you.
他会骑好。
He will ride well.
和他没有害怕。
And he no afraid.
- 我跟你妈妈,去房子。 - 是的,维托利奥。
- I speak with your mother, go to house. - Yes, Vittorio.
旅馆应该有男人。
Lodge should have man.
- 我的丈夫将家里现在任何一天。 - 我不这么认为。
- My husband will be home any day now. - I no think so.
我认为他死了。
I think he dead.
小战士应该有父亲。
Small Warrior should have father.
看,军士,就像我告诉你。
See, Sergeant, just like I told you.
这是我的马,好吧。有我的品牌:“e l“艾德劳。
That's my horse, all right. Got my brand on it: "E.L." Ed Lowe.
他说什么真的吗?
What he says true?
- 是的,那是他的马。-你在哪里得到他吗?
- Yeah, that's his horse. - Where'd you get him?
从自己的农场,我就带他回来。
From his ranch, that's where I'm taking him back.
这就是他能接他。
That's where he can pick him up.
但这是印度的领土,严格的订单将在那里与任何白人。
But that's Indian territory, strict orders against any Whites going in there.
你知道吗,乔,我得到了一个坏的耳朵。我听不见你说的什么。
You know something, Joe, I got a bad ear. I can't hear a thing you're saying.
难道你会喜欢指控他吗?
Aren't you gonna prefer charges against him?
他可能是一个意思,脾气不好的,儿子的任何你想叫他……
He may be a mean, ornery, son-of-anything-you-wanna-call-him...
但他不是马贼。
but he ain't no horse thief.
和我不会叫他一个,他的脸和他的背。
And I'm not gonna call him one, to his face or his back.
你呆在这儿。
You stay here.
我以为Apache总是沉默。
I thought the Apache were always silent.
不是当他们寻求女人。你选择一个。
Not when they seek squaw. You pick one.
什么?
What?
不太好,小战士……
It's not good for Small Warrior...
没有父亲教他如何成为男人。
to be without father to teach him how to be man.
这是我在叫埃米利亚诺・。
This is the one I was calling Emiliano.
非常勇敢,已采取许多头皮。
Very brave, has taken many scalps.
他有六匹马,和两个squaws,但是一个老和很快就会死。
He has six horses, and two squaws, but one old and will soon die.
他的好猎手。
He's good hunter.
从来没有饿,他的窝棚。
Never hungry, his wickiup.
这是一个叫做Kloori是谁。
This is one who is called Kloori.
他有十匹马,一个女人。
He has ten horses, one squaw.
Sachito,勇敢的战士,许多马。
Sachito, brave warrior, many horses.
没有多少squaws击败,唱得很大声。
Not much beat squaws, sings very loud.
- 男孩,去站在我的马。 - 是的,维托利奥。
- Boy, go stand by my horse. - Yes, Vittorio.
小战士从来没有看到眼泪,Apache不哭泣。
Small Warrior never to see tears, Apache does not weep.
首席,你不能让我这样做,我结婚了。
Chief, you can't make me do this, I'm married.
你是傻瓜,你的男人死了。
You are fool, your man dead.
很快来种植雨。如果你的男人回家,然后,好。
Soon come planting rain. If your man come home by then, good.
如果不是,你把Apache勇敢。
If not, you take Apache brave.
记住,时间种植雨。
Remember, time of planting rain.
他有点深入印度领土。
He's getting kind of deep into Indian territory.
,我们也是。
And so are we.
你的叫声吗?你得到报酬优厚。
What are you squawking for? You're getting well paid.
他会使营很快。不要让机会在他之后,我们会回头。
He'll be making camp pretty soon. Don't get a chance at him then, we'll turn back.
安静的,山姆,我听到他们。
Quiet, Sam, I hear them.
来吧,山姆。
Come on, Sam.
这是他的营地,所有权利。
That's his camp, all right.
步枪的消失,必须寻找营地肉。
Rifle's gone, must be out looking for camp meat.
- 你是好的,你不是受伤了。 - 这个锡版照相法救了我。
- You're all right, you're not hurt bad. - This tintype saved me.
做的那件事。
That did it.
现在,我们之间每一个Apache和牧场会接到通知。
Now, every Apache between us and the ranch will be alerted.
他们会让我们切断。
They'll have us cut off.
不,没人在我们和Seddon堡。
No, there's nobody between us and Fort Seddon.
打败它,山姆!
Beat it, Sam!
- 白人了解Apache。 - 一个小。
- White man understand Apache. - A little.
他现在知道他是如何死的。
He know now how he die.
你贴头皮,展示了很多政变
Your coup stick shows many scalps.
是的,很多。很快,你。
Yes, many. Soon, you.
人的头皮会从那里。
Man's scalp would look out of place there.
你把所有你从squaws,幼儿和狗。
You took all yours from squaws, papoose, and dogs.
你的旅馆应该是真正的为你骄傲。
Your lodge should be real proud of you.
你需要长时间死亡。
You will take long time die.
士兵在哪里,白色男人?
Where are soldiers, White man?
- 有多少? - 我不知道,维托利奥。
- How many? - I don't know, Vittorio.
你知道我的名字吗?
You know my name?
我看到你曾经在米德堡条约理事会。
I saw you once at the Treaty Council at Fort Meade.
该条约。
The treaty.
该条约是喜欢沙沙作响的风的白人男子。
The treaty was like rustle of wind to White man.
- 现在你告诉,士兵? - 这,我不知道。
- Now you tell, where are soldiers? - This, I do not know.
-帽子。士兵的帽子。 - 我曾经是一个士兵。
- Hat. Soldier hat. - I was once a soldier.
为什么你在这里Apache土地吗?
Why you here Apache land?
这是我能知道的。
This is for me to know.
我告诉你说侮辱我的首领这一套。
I'm told you speak insults to this one of my chiefs.
美洲狮尖叫的侮辱和很勇敢。
The cougar screams insults and is brave.
一只狼咆哮的侮辱和是一个懦夫。
A coyote howls insults and is a coward.
我们将看到。
We shall see.
美洲狮或土狼。
Cougar or coyote.
你会死在沉默中勇敢地……
You will die bravely in silence...
或者你会像女人带来孩子嚎啕大哭……
or you will wail like woman bringing forth child...
和哀求我们小马士兵正。
and cry out to us where pony-soldiers are.
他声称血吧,你明白吗?
He claims the blood right, you understand?
你的意思是,他说我拍他的哥哥吗?
You mean, he says I shot his brother?
我理解。
I understand.
这样的生活可能落干净。
So that life may ebb cleanly.
忘记你的血液对或加入你的哥哥。
Forget your blood right or join your brother.
你认为你买你现在的生活吗?
You think you buy your life now?
我不认为。
I don't think.
你可能是死是活,我们看到。
You may live or die, we see.
印第安人。
Indians.
这是你的男人吗?
Is this your man?
说,这是你的男人吗?
Speak, is this your man?
- 是的,这是我的丈夫。 - 白人…
- Yes, this is my husband. - White man...
你住在Apache,这很好。
you lived with the Apache, that's good.
你知道小战士应该教…
You know how Small Warrior should be taught that...
他的儿子被尊敬的人叫窝棚维托利奥。
he be honored son of wickiup of one who's called Vittorio.
看像鹰,请耐心,因为《海狸》……
Watch like the hawk, be patient as the beaver...
勇敢,彪马,那他可能学好。
brave as puma, that he may learn well.
知道它,然后……
Know it, then...
或者你的死会死很久之前你欢迎。
or your dying will be long before you welcome death.
- 更多的咖啡吗?-不,谢谢。
- More coffee? - No, thanks.
- 你要做什么? - 要修理你的衬衫。
- What are you gonna do? - Gonna fix up your shirt.
之前,我告诉你一些。
Not before I show you something.
- 给你这是埃德? - 我把它从他的身体。
- Did Ed give you this? - I took it off his body.
他死了。
He's dead.
试图告诉你之前。
Tried to tell you before.
可笑,我不惊讶。
Funny, I'm not surprised.
也许是因为我一直都清楚,只是不愿承认自己。
Perhaps because I knew all along, just wouldn't admit it to myself.
- 嗨, Emberato, 你没死,你呢? - 你好,约翰尼。
- Hi, Emberato, you didn't die, did you? - Hello, Johnny.
小心。
Be careful.
我想告诉你一些东西, Emberato。我的印度的象征。
I wanna show you something, Emberato. My Indian emblem.
维托利奥给了我,没有他,妈妈?
Vittorio gave it to me, didn't he, Mom?
- 他是一个伟大的喜欢约翰尼了。 - 或许救了你的命和矿山。
- He's taken a great liking to Johnny. - Probably saved your life and mine.
印度人非常看重男性儿童的地方。
Indians place great value on male children.
他们也将一个伟大的价值对死去的好。
They also place a great value on dying well.
Ed死好了吗?
Did Ed die well?
我把它放在我的枕头。
I keep it under my pillow.
他死了好。
He died well.
当约翰尼太老了,当他被告知……
When Johnny's old enough, when he has to be told...
它会使他骄傲。
it will make him proud.
在这里, Emberato。我是一个首席现在。这不是很美妙吗?
Here it is, Emberato. I'm a chief now. Isn't it wonderful?
- 不是吗? - 是的,约翰尼。
- Isn't it? - Yes, Johnny.
- 你妈妈在什么地方? - 选择豆瓣菜。
- Where's your mother? - Picking watercress.
- 任何运气吗?今天早上 - 不是咬。
- Any luck? - Not a bite this morning.
看到太阳在哪里?
See where the sun is?
- 那里。 - 是的,在你的颈后。
- Up there. - Yeah, on the back of your neck.
你投下影子。
You're casting a shadow.
如果你能看到它,鱼可以看到它。
If you can see it, the fish can see it.
总是与太阳鱼在你的脸。其他银行的这个地方。
Always fish with the sun in your face. The other bank's the place.
- 也就是说,如果你想听我的看法。 - 天哪,Emberato,我想听听你的意见。
- That is, if you want my opinion. - Gosh, Emberato, I want your opinion.
但是妈妈不让我去那边。
But Mama won't let me go over there.
- 为什么不呢? - 我不会游泳。
- Why not? - I can't swim.
- 你不能什么? - 我不会游泳。
- You can't what? - I can't swim.
- 你多大了?- 6。
- How old are you? - Six.
- 帮助他,他不会游泳。 - 时间他学习。每个人都应该游泳。
- Help him, he can't swim. - Time he learned. Everybody should swim.
只是在你面前伸出,抓一把水。
Just reach out in front of you and grab a handful of water.
把它回到你。
Pull it back towards you.
不太快。这是我学会了。
Not too fast. That's the way I learned.
- 我做了它, Emberato, 我做到了。 - 好的。
- I did it, Emberato, I did it. - Good.
- 他怎么回来的? - 游泳。
- How will he get back? - Swim.
嗯,他可能会被淹死。
Well, he might drown.
- 那么,你去找他。 - 我不会游泳,要么。
- Well, then, you go get him. - I can't swim, either.
安吉,有…
Angie, there's...
一些我必须告诉你。我想告诉你。
something I've got to tell you. I tried to tell you.
和它不会是容易的。 - 那就不要说吗。
- And it isn't going to be easy. - Then don't say it yet.
看看月亮。
Just look at the moon.
多么奇怪的看起来在这个季度。
How odd it looks in this quarter.
当我还是个孩子的时候,我的母亲曾经告诉我这是一个跷跷板。
When I was a child, my mother used to tell me it was a teeter-totter.
你知道的,倾斜的木板一个孩子玩。
You know, the tilted plank a child plays on.
我想印度人有的话。
I suppose the Indians have a word for it.
是的, bermarga。 这是种植的月亮。
Yeah, bermarga. It's the planting moon.
印度人不会种植玉米,除非月球的那样。
Indians won't plant their corn unless the moon's like that.
你喜欢生活在Apache,不是吗?
You liked living with the Apache, didn't you?
安琪,我刚要告诉你这个。
Angie, I've just got to tell you this.
我没有说谎。
I'm not much for lying.
上次我在这里,在维给我吗?
The last time I was here, before Vittorio brought me?
是的。
Yes.
我骑马分派一些之后,然后来到登。
I rode dispatch some after that, then came to Seddon.
有麻烦了。
There was trouble.
我杀了一个人。
I killed a man.
呆着别动。有人在那些柳树。
Stay still. Somebody in those willows.
别开枪,白人。
Don't shoot, White man.
小战士有刀。他睡与它。
Small Warrior has knife. He sleeps with it.
- 你是在家里吗? - 在房子。
- You were in the house? - In house.
窝棚空的地方没有儿子。我空的窝棚。
Wickiup empty place without sons. Mine empty wickiup.
你最好告诉那个勇敢的回到河岸不要在水里走。
You better tell that brave back at the creek bank not to walk in the water.
我差点杀了他几分钟前。
I almost killed him a few minutes ago.
几乎把射击他。
Almost threw a shot at him.
他很轻。将学习。
He very young. Will learn.
- 如果他住。 - 你是Apache。
- Lf he lives. - You are Apache.
现在,听我,小马士兵靠近。
Now, hear me, pony-soldiers are near.
很快将战斗战斗记忆。他们会来这里第一。
Soon will be fought remembered fight. They will come here first.
- 你不会跟他们一起去,白人。-我不会。
- You will not go with them, White man. - I will not.
领袖会怀疑你的小马士兵。
Leader of pony-soldiers will question you.
你会说你看过Apache落后西方。
You will say you have seen Apache trailing to the west.
这个我不会做。
This I won't do.
- 你不会吗?-我不会。
- You will not? - I will not.
你有好男人,珍惜他。
You have good man, treasure him.
他们安装了现在下来的孤峰。
They're mounting up now down by the butte.
我没有听到一点声音。
I don't hear a thing.
有八个我想说的,或者是9。
There's eight of them I'd say, or maybe nine.
- 有什么东西在那些树。 - 那是一只松鼠。我们的谈话把他唤醒。
- There's something in those trees. - That's a squirrel. Our talking woke him up.
他熄灭。其中有9个。
He's put out. There's nine of them.
我爱你。
I love you.
我想我不应该这样说的…
I suppose I shouldn't have said that...
和我的丈夫死了那么短的时间。
with my husband dead so short a time.
我不猜人的心灵得到任何一个日历。
I don't guess people's hearts got anything to do with a calendar.
你是如此美好,拒绝谎言,维托利奥。
You were so wonderful, refusing to lie for Vittorio.
他在考验我。印度人讨厌谎言。
He was testing me. Indians hate lies.
我想我必须有同样的感觉…
And I guess I got to feel the same way...
但是,偶尔一个小伙子必须……
but, once in a while a fella's got to...
谎言如果它会让别人更容易。
lie if it'll make it easier on someone else.
队伍,停止!
Troop, halt!
准备下车。
Prepare to dismount.
下马!
Dismount!
女士,先生,我可以介绍我自己吗?中尉麦凯,队伍D,8日骑兵。
Madam and sir, may I present myself? Lt. McKay, Troop D, 8th cavalry.
- 嗨,本州,你老客舱强盗。 - 嗨,浅黄色。
- Hi, Hondo, you old cabin robber. - Hi, Buff.
中尉,这这是本州巷。
Lieutenant, this here is Hondo Lane.
他赤手空拳一些和骑调度一些骑兵。
He's scouted some and ridden dispatch some for the cavalry.
-我不认为我知道这个夫人。 - 这是罗伊女士,中尉。
- I don't reckon I know this here lady. - This is Ms. Lowe, Lieutenant.
你人是幸运的。显然,维托利奥…
You people are lucky. Obviously, Vittorio...
和他的变节的乐队刚刚发生不发现这个隐藏的山谷。
and his renegade band just happened not to find this hidden valley.
-维托利奥是这里很多。 - 和你住吗?
- Vittorio's been here lots. - And you lived?
一个男人站在维卓智是一家了?
One Ione man stood off Vittorio?
没有男子站了Apache卓智是一家。他让我们住在这里。
No Ione man stands off the Apache. He lets us live here.
有近100人死亡的定居者在盆地……
There are almost 100 dead settlers in the basin...
通过这个懦弱的罪犯杀害。
scalped by this cowardly criminal.
维托利奥可能是一个犯罪的书,我不知道。
Vittorio may be a criminal by the books, I don't know.
但如果他是一个懦夫,它并没有出现但。
But if he's a coward, it hasn't showed up yet.
- 阿门,兄弟。 - 我必须同意你,雷恩。
- Amen, brother. - I must disagree with you, Mr. Lane.
他在我们面前跑了200英里。
He's run before us for 200 miles.
印度人有一个故事告诉他们的轻人……
Indians have a story they tell their young ones...
关于一个猎人追一只猫,他抓住了它。
about a hunter who chased a wild cat until he caught it.
然后是反过来的。
Then it was the other way around.
这个故事追溯到进一步比印度人。
The story goes back further than the Indians.
它的最初归因于第一罗马军队进入鞑靼。
It's originally attributed to the first Roman army to enter Tartary.
了一个泼妇的士兵叫着。
The soldier caught a Tartar and yelled out.
警官叫回来他进来与他的囚犯。
The officer called back for him to come in with his prisoner.
他回答说,“鞑靼人不让我。”
And he replied, "The Tartar won't let me."
这是一个最喜欢的故事上校的玉米……
That was one of the favorite stories of Col. Mays...
谁教骑兵战术点。
who teaches cavalry tactics at the Point.
这个故事是全球。
The story is world-wide.
你有多久没有那个学校,中尉?
How long have you been out of that school, Lieutenant?
69毕业先生,类。
Graduated class '69, sir.
这是70,不是吗?
This is '70, ain't it?
我只是不能跟上。我为了得到一个日历,但是然后我忘记。
I just can't seem to keep up with the years. I meant to get a calendar, but then I forget.
说,谁是美国的总统了吗?
Say, who's President of these United States now?
尤利西斯・s・格兰特。
Ulysses S. Grant.
你知道,我投票一次。我被调到独立投票时间周围。
You know, I voted once. I was down in Independence around voting time.
和同伴过来给了我2美元如果我投票给一个名叫泰勒。
And a fellow come up to me and offered me $2 if I'd vote for a man named Taylor.
和我喝的是...
And I was drinking...
当时喝一点。和我...  $ 2没有持续...
drinking a little at the time. And I... The $2 didn't last...
罗伊太太,莱恩先生,我的订单做一个扫描到双峰。
Mrs. Lowe, Mr. Lane, my orders are to make a sweep as far as Twin Buttes.
我的男人会今晚露宿。我们将继续双峰明天……
My men'll bivouac here tonight. We'll go on to Twin Buttes tomorrow...
明天晚上返回护送你和你的男孩到安全。
return tomorrow night to escort you and your boy out to safety.
如果你原谅我,夫人,我必须看到我的男人是正确的。扎营
If you'll excuse me, madam, I must see that my men are properly encamped.
很好,很轻。
Very nice and very young.
他对可恶的肯定是,夫人。
He for doggone sure is, ma'am.
- 你多久在这巡逻吗? - 这是20天。
- How long you been out on this patrol? - This is the 20th day.
我们搜集了大约八个家庭回到那里,这是所有有离开。
We've rounded up about eight families back there, that's all there are left.
我们会接他们出来的路上。
We're gonna pick them up on the way out.
这里有许多头皮了,本州。
There've been many a scalp took, Hondo.
- 你知道维托利奥,别你吗? - 我做。
- You know where Vittorio is, don't you? - I do.
这个男孩中尉的捉你杀死了。
This boy Lieutenant's gonna get you killed.
美国童子军已经得把这些受过教育的轻军官。
Us scouts has got to get these young officers educated.
约翰尼,进去,开始为我的盘子。
Johnny, go in and set out the plates for me.
本州,如果你的朋友想和我们一起吃, Mr...
Hondo, if your friend would like to eat with us, Mr...
水牛吗? Mr...
Buffalo? Mr...
我已经知道你8或10。你必须有一个姓。
I've known you for 8 or 10 years. You must have a last name.
嗯,我当然有一个姓,你把我当成什么了?
Well, of course I got a last name, what do you think I am?
我知道你在,但是有一个女士礼物。
I know what you are, but there's a lady present.
罗伊太太,我的名字是贝克。这是它是什么,水牛贝克。
Mrs. Lowe, my name is Baker. That's what it is, Buffalo Baker.
嗯,你可以和我们一起吃然后,贝克先生,洗。
Well, you may eat with us then, Mr. Baker, and wash.
有一盆和毛巾在板凳上的水壶,和肥皂。
There's a basin on the bench and a towel on the jug, and soap.
你知道,有一些关于这个地方 …
You know, there is something about this place...
- 我知道这让我想起。 - 我的牧场。
- I know what it reminds me of. - My ranch.
在加州。
In California.
我打死一只鹿马上门廊在孤峰就这样。
I shot a deer right off your front porch on a butte just like that.
与克里克下面和平顶山所有扩散。
With a crick down below and the mesas all spreading out.
让我打包带回去。
Made me pack it back.
- 你有一个地方,看起来像这个吗? - 东圣迪马斯的。
- You have a place that looks like this? - East of San Dimas.
多么美妙。
How wonderful.
你要去哪里你需要什么样的水。
You're getting to where you kind of take to that water.
每次我洗我的脸……
Every time I wash my face...
我觉得你和那天晚上登的,当你疲惫不堪的我。
I think of you and that night at Seddon's, when you whacked me.
你开除了一个颚齿,它要伤害如此糟糕我不得不去……
You busted off a jaw tooth, and it got to hurting so bad I had to go to...
理发师和他挖出剩下的。
the barber and have him dig out the rest of it.
我才看到你那一天,我已经把你的太阳。
Did I catch you that day, I'd have set your sun.
这是最后一天早上你见过。
That's the last morning you'd ever seen.
“本州巷,一等奖,温彻斯特武器。”
"Hondo Lane, first prize, Winchester Arms."
你总是喜欢这种步枪。一直想要一个自己的新问题。
Always liked this rifle of yours. Always wanted one of the new issue myself.
保持你的手从它。
Keep your hands off it.
我认识他十,他从来没有对我说一个友好的话。
I've known him 10 years, and he's never spoken a friendly word to me.
- 我不喜欢你。 - 认为。
- I don't like you. - Figured that.
但是现在我图是他可能很想给我那步枪。
But now I figure is how he might admire to give me that rifle.
你看,约半天了,我遇到一些Seddon尸体。
You see, about a half day out of Seddon, I come across some bodies.
其中之一是这个女士的丈夫。
One of them was this here lady's husband.
有许多马在赛道。
There was a lot of horse tracks around there.
其中一些属于,栗你骑。
Some of them belonged to that there chestnut you were riding.
这一遭遗弃的马蹄。
That one with the cast-off horseshoe.
是的,先生,这是一个强大的漂亮小设置你有自己这里。
Yes, sir, it's a mighty nice little set-up you got yourself here.
漂亮的农场。漂亮的女人。
Nice ranch. Pretty woman.
你可以让自己死亡这样的谈话。
You could get yourself killed talking like this.
或者我可以得到新型温彻斯特……
Or I could get that new-fashioned Winchester...
自从他bushwhacked这女士的丈夫。
since he bushwhacked this lady's husband.
她才知道,我想她不会看他像……
Did she know that, I figure she wouldn't look at him like...
他是高的小公鸡每支派的从这里到盐的水。
he was the high cockalorum of every tribe from here to Salt Water.
本州。
Hondo.
我想告诉你。
I tried to tell you.
罗伊太太,我们准备离开。
Mrs. Lowe, we're ready to leave.
Lane先生吗?
Mr. Lane?
- Stridon。 -是的,先生。
- Stridon. - Yes, sir.
- 构成了部队,列的两个。-是的,先生。
- Form the troops, column of twos. - Yes, sir.
我希望你能陪我们到双峰。
I want you to accompany us as far as Twin Buttes.
没有时间浪费了,所以我很感激如果你会套上马鞍。
Haven't any time to lose, so I'd be obliged if you'd saddle up.
-我不会。 - 你不会吗?
- I'm not going. - You're not going?
- 没错。 - 但是为什么呢?
- That's right. - But why?
- 给我的字。-你的话给谁?
- Gave my word. - Your word to whom?
-维托利奥。 - 显然是一个词给一个……
- Vittorio. - Surely a word given to an...
- 印度暴徒也不会…… - 先生,当我给我的话,我把它。
- Indian desperado wouldn't be... - Mister, when I give my word, I keep it.
现在我将给你一个忠告…
Now I'll give you a piece of advice...
只有一个家庭在这里之间和双峰……
there's only one family between here and Twin Buttes...
和你太迟去做什么好。
and you're too late to do them any good.
所以你最好收集什么移民你然后和离开这里。
So you better gather up what settlers you have and hightail it out of here.
先生,我有我的订单,这些订单将被执行。
Sir, I have my orders, and these orders will be executed.
太太。
Ma'am.
准备挂载。
Prepare to mount.
挂载。
Mount.
向前……
Forward...
喂!
ho!
- 安吉。 - 我现在不能和你谈。我不得不认为。
- Angie. - I can't talk now. I have to think.
我要把你的东西外。
I'll put your things outside.
- 我走之前我想解释什么。 - 是吗?
- Before I go I want to explain something. - Yes?
它没有发生在你听到它的低。
It didn't happen in the low way you heard it.
- 我没有奇袭。 - 我决不认为你做的。
- I didn't bushwhack. - I never for a moment thought you did.
- 但你杀了他。 - 我没有任何选择……
- But you killed him. - I didn't have any choice...
- 他割断我...   - 我应该知道。
- he cut loose at me... - I should have known that.
我应该知道你在撒谎,让我觉得他的好话。
I should have known you were lying to make me think well of him.
可怜的艾德。我猜他不是那种人死好。
Poor Ed. I guess he wasn't the sort of man to die well.
对不起现在我恨他那么多。
Sorry now I hated him so much.
我想他不能帮助懦弱和自私。
I guess he couldn't help being weak and selfish.
-我只是没有任何选择。 - 我知道。
- I just didn't have any choice. - I know that.
你会对我有不同的感觉吗?
You're gonna feel differently about me?
没有人控制他们的感受。
No one has any control over the way they feel.
我永远不会改变我对你的感觉。
I'm never going to change the way I feel about you.
但是……
But...
他怎么样?
what about him?
是的。
Yeah.
想有些事情不能 …
Guess there are some things that just can't...
他会是一个好男人。
He's gonna be a good man.
良好的扩散到他的肩膀。头工作,太。
Good spread to his shoulders. Head works, too.
其他的夜晚,在你去睡眠,他爬到我的床铺……
Other night, after you went to sleep, he crawled up into my bunk...
,双手环抱着我的脖子。
and put his arms around my neck.
让我觉得有些可笑。
Made me feel kind of funny.
就像他是取决于我。
Like he was depending on me.
很多事情我宁愿做。
Lot of things I'd rather do than this.
你会告诉他吗?
You're going to tell him?
如果我不这样做,别人会。和我有一个肚子充满谎言。
If I don't, somebody else will. And I got a belly full of lies.
看这是什么!
Look what I got!
- 把他的腮像我显示你。 - 确定。
- Hold him by the gills like I showed you. - Sure.
- 约翰尼,我想告诉你一件事。 - 这是一个不错的鲈鱼,不是吗?
- Johnny, I want to tell you something. - It's a nice perch, ain't it?
低音。记住它的头的形状吗?
Bass. Remember the shape of its head?
哦,我忘了。低音有颚,坚持这样。
Oh yeah, I forgot. Bass have a jaw that stick out like this.
我想告诉你的是…
What I wanted to tell you is...
不久以前,一个男人用枪向我扑来。
while back, a man came at me with a gun.
- 我必须杀了他。 - 好的。印度人吗?
- I had to kill him. - Good. Indian?
不,他是一个白人,约翰尼,但我没有任何的选择。他的 …
No, he was a white man, Johnny, but I didn't have any choice. He...
我告诉你向下按柄,然后你不会坚持你自己。
I told you to press down on the shank, and then you won't stick yourself.
不会打破钩,要么。
Won't break the hook, either.
在这里,这种棍子咬东西。这是印度的轻人……
Here, bite down on this stick. That's the way Indian youngsters...
学习不要哭。
learn not to cry.
- 约翰,这个人我杀了…… - 不!
- Johnny, this man I killed... - No!
你在加州的农场,它得太远,对八卦去旅行。
Your ranch in California, it's far, too far for gossip to travel.
去把你的拇指在一些杨梅树叶。
Go wrap your thumb in some bayberry leaves.
你和你的愚蠢的理想。
You and your silly ideals.
你认为真理是最重要的事情。
You think truth is the most important thing.
- 这是衡量一个人。 - 不是一个女人。
- It's the measure of a man. - Not for a woman.
一个男人可以有高尚的情操和姿势。
A man can afford to have noble sentiments and poses.
但是一个女人只有结婚的男人。那是她的真相。
But a woman only has the man she marries. That's her truth.
如果他是没有好处的,那是她的真相仍然。
And if he's no good, that's still her truth.
我嫁给了一个人,一个骗子,一个小偷,一个懦夫。
I married a man who was a liar, a thief, and a coward.
他是一个酒鬼和不忠。
He was a drunkard and unfaithful.
他只有结婚我得到这农场,然后他抛弃了约翰尼和我好。
He only married me to get this ranch, and then he deserted Johnny and me for good.
和那是你对你罚款真理。
And that's your fine truth for you.
- 我能把约翰尼在那? - 不,我猜你不能。
- Could I bring Johnny up on that? - No, I guess you couldn't.
然后你过来和你很好,很好……”
And then you come along and you're good and fine...
和一切不可能希望埃德。
and everything that Ed could never hope to be.
现在,你的虚荣心,你想破坏约翰尼的机会,和我的吗?
And now, with your vanity, you want to spoil Johnny's chances, and mine?
Varlebena。 -什么?
- Varlebena. - What?
当印度人卷起他们的女人寻求仪式……
When the Indians wind up their squaw-seeking ceremony...
他们只说一个词: Varlebena。
they only say one word: Varlebena.
这意味着永远。
It means forever.
永远的。
Forever.
嗯,我们抓住了野猫。帮我们一把,可以吗?
Well, we caught the wild cat. Give us a hand, will you?
我不能理解,我们杀了他的最后一个电荷。
I can't understand, we killed him on the last charge.
维托利奥?
Vittorio?
他们把我们包围。
They had us surrounded.
可以把我们的碎片,然后他们撤回了。
Could've cut us to pieces, then they withdrew.
这就是为什么他们退出。任何时候他们的领袖被杀……
That's why they pulled out. Anytime their leader is killed...
这意味着他们的医学的坏。
that means their medicine's bad.
- 这个可怜的孩子。 - 我们要和这个队伍。
- This poor child. - We're going out with this troop.
-维托利奥死了。 - 不,他不能。
- Vittorio's dead. - No, he can't be.
每个人都死了,轮到他。现在让你的可能性。
Everybody gets dead, it was his turn. Now get your possibles.
我有一些药在机舱内。
I have some medicine in the cabin.
谢谢你,夫人,我是…劳
Thank you, Mrs. Lowe, I'd be...
非常感激如果你会通过人们在第一。
eternally grateful if you'd pass among the men first.
不,你受伤了,我要修理你。
No, you're wounded, I'm going to fix you up.
谢谢你,夫人。这个男人比我陷入更糟糕的境地。
Thank you, ma'am. The men are in worse shape than I am.
来,照他说的做。我们会照顾好他的。
Come on, do as he says. We'll take care of him.
- 军士。-是的,先生?
- Sergeant. - Yes, sir?
拆卸。男人
Dismount the men.
- 结马的马车。-是的,先生。
- Hitch their horses up to the wagon. - Yes, sir.
你会发现的牲口棚里面。
You'll find harness in the barn.
莱恩。
Len.
你想要什么? - 采取四个男人和收集定居者。
- What do you want? - Take four men and gather the settlers.
我们可能会赶上你Errad穿越。
We'll probably catch up with you at Errad Crossing.
威尔逊,麦格拉思,里昂,约翰逊。
Wilson, McGrath, Lyon, Johnson.
- 他是如何? - 他会出。
- How is he? - He'll make out.
不知道多少。领我们进了埋伏圈。
Don't know much. Led us into an ambush.
但我不是他一点也不感到羞愧。弹孔在他的面前。
But I ain't ashamed of him nohow. Bullet holes are in the front of him.
所有这些轻人从点就是这样。
All those youngsters from the Point are like that.
他们必须学习。
They got to learn.
他们学习的部分,部分原因是他们死。
Partly they learn, partly they die.
但是我得浮我坚持和你一样。
But I gotta float my stick same as you.
我从来没见过其中一个我不得不感到羞耻。
I never saw one of them I had to be ashamed of.
加入和继续前进。
Join in and keep moving.
继续下去,那里!
Move it along, there!
快点!
Hurry up!
来,沿着这里!
Come on, move along here!
来吧,快点。
Come on, hurry it up.
圆的马车!
Circle the wagons!
轮着她。
Wheel her around.
坚持住!
Hold on!
呆在车上。让大家在马车。
Stay in the wagon. Keep everybody in the wagons.
和不放松。
And don't unhitch.
本州!
Hondo!
所有这些圆的做的是保护马。我们得把一些马车了。
All this circle's doing is protect the horses. We gotta turn some wagons over.
和呆在这儿吗?这就是他们的期望。
And stay here? That's what they expect.
我们必须做他们不期望。
We gotta do what they don't expect.
这就是为什么所有的重型火炮的在布法罗的马车。
That's why all the heavy artillery's in Buffalo's wagon.
水牛!
Buffalo!
中尉,趴下。你准备好了,迷吗?
Lieutenant, get down. Are you ready, Buff?
- 我出生做好准备。 - 走吧。
- I was born ready. - Let's go.
圆的马车。
Circle the wagons.
靠近。
Close up.
呆下来!
Stay down!
警官!
Sergeant!
- 我不想是一个Apache,妈妈。-现在,你安静点。
- I don't want to be an Apache, Mama. - Now, you be quiet.
我们要摆脱所有的权利。现在,帮助我,快点。
We're going to get out all right. Now, help me, hurry.
- 准备好了再一次,迷吗? - 我告诉你,我出生做好准备。
- Ready again, Buff? - As I told you, I was born ready.
把我你的刀。
Throw me your knife.
滚开!
Get out of here!
好吧,本州!
All right, Hondo!
他们不遵循。
They're not following.
领导人的死。他们会举行祈祷仪式,选择一个新的。
Leader's dead. They'll powwow and pick a new one.
- 我们摆脱麻烦如果我们赶快。 - 我要去开车吗?
- We're out of trouble if we get a move on. - And am I going to get to drive?
在我们到达圣迪马斯,你会成为一个顶级卡车驾驶员,儿子。
Before we get to San Dimas, you'll be a top teamster, son.
- 你好,中尉? - 好,谢谢你。
- How are you, Lieutenant? - Fine, thanks to you.
和你都是正确的,由于伦尼。他射,印度经常你的背部。
And you're all right, thanks to Lennie. He shot that Indian offen your back.
- 谢谢。 - 与你的步枪。
- Thanks. - With your rifle.
这是他的。
It's his.
看起来不像我们需要它今天多。
Don't look like we'll be needing it much more today.
一般骗子在一个月内将在这里有一个很大的力。
General Crook will be here within a month with a large force.
- 这将结束的Apache。 - 是的。
- That'll be the end of the Apache. - Yeah.
结束一种生活方式。
End of a way of life.
太糟糕了,这是一个好方法。
Too bad, it's a good way.
马车前进!
Wagons forward!